(upbeat music)
- Hello English learners, welcome
back to English Pod, my name is Marco.
- And I'm Erica.
- And today we're bringing you
our great suspense, scary series.
- Our thriller.
- Our thriller, new guy in town, part four.
- All right, well, I don't
wanna give you any
hints about what will
happen in this dialogue.
- Yes, it's totally unexpected.
So, so let's listen to our
dialogue and then we'll
come back and talk about
some of the great vocabulary.
(upbeat music)
- All right, drag her, drag her
over here and help me tire up.
- I can't believe she fell for it.
She is a lot more gullible than I thought.
- Well, you gotta admit,
my acting was brilliant.
- Oh, whatever.
I was the one that convinced her to come.
Look, she's waking up.
- What's going on, Ellen?
What are you doing?
- The cats out of the bag, you witch.
You can stop pretending now.
- Yeah, Lois, we know who you are.
Now, we want some answers.
Why are you here?
(upbeat music)
(laughing)
- Please, you're dealing with it.
- You can't stop me.
- Brian, no.
(upbeat music)
- Well, I certainly didn't
see that one coming.
- I know everyone thought
that our mind was a vampire.
- I know.
- And now it turns out
that they were acting.
- Yeah, crazy.
- Crazy, huh?
- Strange things happen here on a hot pot.
- All right, so why don't we take a look
at some of the language that
we saw in language takeaway?
- Language takeaway.
- Well, we have three words for you
here that we heard in the dialogue.
And the first one, our mind
tells Ellen to drag her over here.
- Right, drag, drag.
So when you drag something
or somebody, you pull them
across the floor, or pull
them across the ground.
- Pull them, but you don't
actually pick them up, right?
- No, yeah, their body is
still touching the ground.
- Okay, so just imagine
if you have a really
heavy suitcase, it
doesn't have any wheels.
You gotta drag it across the floor, right?
- I've been there, it's happened to me too.
So drag.
- All right, and then he says, tie her up.
Tie her up, tie somebody up.
So to tie somebody up.
- To use rope and put it around a
person so that they cannot move.
- Right, so you take
rope, you tie a person up.
And it's always used like this, right?
Tie somebody up.
- Yes, tie him up.
- Tie that up.
Tie that up, okay, and our last word.
- I like this one, fools.
- Fools, fools.
- So our singular would be fool.
- Yeah, F-O-O-L.
- So what's a fool?
- Well, a fool is a stupid person.
- Right, a person that
doesn't know - Yes.
- Something or an ignorant person.
- All right, well, Lois thinks
that Armon - Ellen, our fools.
- Exactly, apparently she got really angry
and managed to escape from the
chair or whatever, she was tied up, right?
- Well, the dialogue was a little bit fast.
There was a lot of sound effects as well.
- Yep.
- So let's listen to this dialogue.
Again, we're gonna
slow it down a little bit,
and I'm sure it's gonna be a
little bit easier to understand.
- All right, drag her over
here and help me tie her up.
- I can't believe she fell for it.
- She is a lot more
gullible than I thought.
- Well, you gotta admit,
my acting was brilliant.
- Whatever, I was the one
that convinced her to come.
Look, she's waking up.
- What's going on, Ellen?
What's you doing?
- The cats out of the bag, you witch.
You can stop pretending now.
- Yeah, Lois, we know who you are.
Now, we want some answers.
- Why are you here?
(laughing)
- Fools, you don't know
who you're dealing with.
You can't stop me.
Run.
(upbeat music)
- Well, Marco, I noticed in this dialogue,
there's a lot of words
and phrases that we can
use to talk about lying
or fooling somebody.
- Exactly, there is a lot
of language about lying.
So let's take a look
at it in fluency builder.
Fluency builder.
- All right, so, in fluency builder
today, let's take a look at four phrases.
The first one, fell for it.
- Fell for it.
- I can't believe she fell for it.
- Okay, so it's not
that she physically fell.
- No, no, okay.
- But she believed the lie.
- She believed the
lie, you fell for the lie.
- Yeah.
- We have some examples,
so we can understand
this phrase, fell for
it a little bit better.
- Example one.
- You might seem like a
nice guy, but don't fall for it.
He's a jerk.
- Example two.
- I can't believe I fell for your lies.
- Example three.
- I told my mom I was going
to the library and she fell for it.
- All right, well, that's
a lot clearer to me.
I noticed that we have
the preposition it here.
- Yeah, it is at the end.
And it's referring to the
lie or the joke or the story.
She fell for the story, but you
wouldn't say, she fell for the story.
You would say she fell for it.
- Yeah, so these three words always,
always, always go to get our fell for it.
So don't forget the it.
- Don't forget the it.
Okay, let's take a look at her second word.
- Gullable.
- So Ellen thinks that Lois was gullible.
- Right, a gullible person.
- Yeah, gullible.
- A gullible person is
somebody that always believes.
- Yes, they always fall for it.
- They always fall for it.
- Yeah.
- They believe anything you say.
So I know you were a little bit
gullible when you were younger, right?
- Yeah, that's true.
You know what, my
grandmother used to tell me
every year she would
say, oh, I'm 35, I'm 35.
And I really believed her
until I was about 12 years old.
- Wow, so you were really gullible.
- Really gullible.
- Oh, you're not anymore.
- No, I know better.
- All right, so gullible, gullible person.
Okay, now let's look at the next phrase.
The cats out of the bag.
The cat is out of the bag.
Okay, so again, it's not little.
It's not like you had a cat
in a bag and you let it out.
And nice idiom here,
meaning the truth is out.
- The truth is that we discover the truth.
- Yes, so imagine
that the cat is the truth.
- Right, and it escaped.
- Yes.
- Okay, so the cat's out of the bag.
The truth is that we know the truth now.
- Yep.
- Okay, and our last phrase, pretending.
- Pretending.
- So Lois was pretending
to be a normal housewife.
Let's listen to some examples
of how we would use pretending.
- Example one, pretend that you're
my boyfriend and he'll go away.
Example two.
- I can't believe Lucy
pretended to be sick.
- Example three, you forgot my birthday.
Don't pretend that everything is okay.
- Okay, so pretending is acting like
you are somebody that you are not.
- Yes, or yeah, it's
sort of like acting a lie.
- Okay, so for example, on Halloween, everyone
dresses up as a monster or Spider-Man,
something so everyone
pretends to be that character,
but they are not.
- Yes.
- Okay, pretending to pretend.
Okay, so let's listen to
our dialogue one more time
and then we'll come
back and talk some more.
(upbeat music)
(dramatic music)
- All right, drag her over
here and help me tire up.
- I can't believe she fell for it.
She is a lot more gullible than I thought.
- Well, you gotta admit,
my acting was brilliant.
- Whatever, I was the one
that convinced her to come.
Look, she's waking up.
What's going on, Ellen?
What's you doing?
- The cats out of the bag, you witch.
You can stop pretending now.
- Yeah, Lois, we know who you are.
Now, we want some answers.
Why are you here?
(dramatic music)
(laughing)
- You can't stop me.
- Right, no.
(dramatic music)
- Okay, so what do you
think will happen in part five?
- I have no idea.
(laughing)
- Well, what do you guys
think will happen in part five?
Apparently, our mom
is in a vampire anymore.
- But Lois is a witch.
- Who's Ellen?
- What sort of twist are we gonna see here?
- She an alien.
- Oh my God.
- We don't know what will happen, but
you can tell us what you think will happen.
Come to our
website at EnglishPod.
com and leave all your questions and
comments and maybe your story ideas.
- Yes, Marco and I are always around
to answer your questions and
to respond to your comments.
- Okay.
- Guys, I think we're at a time for today,
but thanks for listening.
- And we'll see you next time.
- Goodbye.
(upbeat music)